The Northern Gateway is now configured and registered in the Lorawan network server of your choice.
There is one more step to be done on the network server.
It's the device registration.
By doing this, our network server will authorize our device LoRaWAN frame to reach the application
server. In a network server,
we can register thousands of devices, but if you want to keep things tidy, then we can grab devices that
belongs to the same use case.
Usually the group created is called an application, but on other networks servers, you might find
other names. Anyway,
in our example, we'll create an application, and in this application we will register two devices,
one with ABP activation mode and another one with a OTAA activation mode.
Great.
So let's go, on the TTN server.
Last time we used the Gateway Section, but now we need to go on the Application Section, and to create
an application, we just need to hit the "create application" button.
Our application name will be training-usmb, and we press the creation application button.
That's it.
It's that simple.
And now we can add new devices.
So I click on my new application.
In the device section, I will register a new ABP end device.
Even if this end device is part of the TTN repository.
I will register it manually to show you all the steps.
So in our case, I choose the European 868 megahertz frequency band.
I choose the right LoRaWAN version of my end device.
In my case, it's 1.0.3 and in this subsection, isolate the right activation mode.
For this demonstration, we're dealing with ABP.
Now, I still have to fill out the LoRaWAN information.
And first, the server ask for the DevEUI.
In my case, I use the one written on my end device.
Then comes the specific LoRaWAN information that we always need : Device Address? that I can generate.
Application Session Key and Networks Session Key that I can generate as well.
Then finally, I can give the device a name to personalize it.
In my case, I will call it device1-abp.
So it's these three parameters that I will have to configure in the end device, and that's what I will
do later.
First, I will register another and device, but this time with a OTAA activation Mode.
So I'm back on my console and in the device section, I'm going to manually register a new OTAA and device.
In our case, I choose the European 868 megahertz frequency band.
I choose the right LoRaWAN version of my device.
In my case, it's 1.0.3.
I can check that I'm already in the OTAA activation mode.
First, I need to give the devEUI.
I've got one for my device already so I can copy it here.
Otherwise, I could have generated it.
Secondly, I need to provide the AppEUI.
As I said, we won't use it much.
And this LoRaWAN server
even propose me to fill it in with zeros.
That's what I'm going to do.
So now we still have to provide the App Key.
In my case, I generate one.
Finally, I can personalize my device with a name, and I call it device1-otaa.
When I hit the register and device button, I've got the overview of my device information and obviously
I can find the EUI.
The app EUI and of course, the AppKey.
So it's these three parameters that I will have to configure in my end device.
And that's what we're going to do now with these two LoRaWAN devices.